Guide to the North Carolina State University, Department of Entomology Drawings and Papers
North Carolina State University, Department of Entomology Drawings and Papers
- Taxonomic Illustrations, 1967-1990; 1967 1990; 8.517 archival boxes
  - White Peach Scale (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - White Pine Aphid (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - White Pine Weevil (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Wild Bees (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Wild Cherry Pouch Gall (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Willow Sawfly (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Winter Grain Mite (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Wireworms (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Wooly Alder Aphid (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Wooly Apple Aphid (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Wooly Pine Scale (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Wooly Whitefly (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Yaupon Psyllid (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Yellow Jacket (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Yellownecked Caterpillar (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Yellow Scale (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Yellowstriped Armyworm (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Yellow Sugarcane Aphid (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Yellow Woolybear (Box 17, Folder 20)
- Oversized Illustrations, 1970-1980; 1970 1980; 2.5 linear feet
  This series contains nearly all illustrative material 11 x 17 in. or larger, and is comprised of three subseries: Leafhopper 1, Leafhopper 2, and General Entomology Illustrations. The first two subseries, consisting of over 900 figure groupings on matte board, are taxonomic illustrations of species of the order Homoptera, 1970-1980. The third subseries, over 400 more figures in a similar format, contains various entomological illustrations, ranging from pest control equipment to insect morphology, 1970-1980.
  - Leafhopper 1, 1970-1980
    - Figures 1-150 (Flatbox 18)
    - Figures 151-299 (Flatbox 19)
    - Figures 300-499 (Flatbox 20)
    - Figures 450-598 (Oversizeflatbox 21)
    - Figures 599-750 (Flatbox 22)
    - Figures 751-905 (Flatbox 23)
  - Leafhopper 2, 1970-1980
    - Figures 1-200 (Box 24)
    - Figures 201-419 (Box 25)
  - General Entomology Illustrations, 1970-1990
    - Figures (Box 26)
    - Figures (Box 27)
- James R. Baker Papers, 1966-2000; 1966 2000; 1 linear feet
  This series is comprised of two subseries: Publications, and Correspondence and Videotape. The first subseries primarily contains entomological publications edited (or coedited) and authored (or coauthored) by Baker, the curator of the collection, and published by the North Carolina Agricultural Extension Service (later Cooperative Extension Service), 1973-2000. These are pest control manuals, as well as copies of a pest control informational serial, Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes. Included with these publications is correspondence regarding revised editions prepared by Baker. Also in this subseries are other professional writings, including some unpublished papers, by Baker, 1968-1994. The second subseries contains correspondence of Baker regarding professional publications and taxonomy, nearly all while he was a research assistant at North Carolina State University and a research fellow at the University of Kansas, 1966-1975. Also included in this subseries is a VHS-format videocassette tape, Documental Control Integrado de la Vinchuca, an informational video about control of the vinchuca, or South American kissing bug, produced by the Instituto de Investigacones Agricolas, Universidad Autonoma Gabriel Rene Moreno, Santa Cruz de la Sierra, Bolivia, 1998.
  - Publications, 1973-2000
    - Insect and Related Pests of Flowers and Foliage Plants (AG-136) (revised), 1994 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Insect and Related Pests of Flowers and Foliage Plants (AG-136), 1984 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Insect and Related Pests of Flowers and Foliage Plants (AG-136): General Correspondence, 1978-1996 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Insect and Related Pests of Shrubs (AG-189): General Correspondence, 1979-1988 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Insect Control on Ornamental Plants in and Around the House (AG-217), 1981 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - "Insect Control on Ornamental Plants in and Around the House" (Circular 561), 1973-1975 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "Insect Control on Ornamental Plants in and Around the House" (Circular 561): General Correspondence, 1973, undated (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Insect and Other Pests Associated with Turf (AG-268), 1982 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Insect and Other Pests Associated with Turf (AG-268): General Correspondence, 1979-1982, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Insect and Related Pests of North Carolina Field Crops (AG-271): General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Insect and Other Pests of People and Animals (AG-369) (revised), 2000 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Insect and Other Pests of Man and Animals (AG-369), 1986 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Insect and Other Pests of People and Animals (AG-369): General Correspondence, 1984-1999 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Master Gardener Insect Guide for Ornamentals and Turf (AG-433) (revised), 1990 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Master Gardener Insect Guide for Ornamentals and Turf (AG-433), 1987 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Woody Ornamental Mites and Insects in Western North Carolina (no number), 1988 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 1-20), 1974-1985 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 21-40), 1977-1983 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 41-60), 1983-1984 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 61-70), 1983-1986 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 1-35) (revised), 1994-1997 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 36-70) (revised), 1994-1999 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - "Ornamentals and Turf Insect Notes" (Nos. 71-108), 1994-1997 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Other Professional Writings, 1968-1975 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Other Professional Writings, 1987, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Other Professional Writings, 1991-1994 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Videotape, 1966-1975, 1998
    - General Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1968-1975 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Documental Control Integrado de la Vinchuca", 1998 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Documental Control Integrado de la Vinchuca" videotape, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      A copy of this VHS must be made prior to patron use.
- Publications
  - Entomological Nomenclature and Literature / W. J. Chamberlin, inscribed "To Mr. J. G. Baker Compliments of W. J. Chamberlin" and letter from W. J. Chamberlin to Gerard Baker, University Library, Urbana, Illinois, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Entomological Nomenclature and Literature / W. J. Chamberlin inscribed "Compliments of the Author W. J. C." [2nd ed.], 1945 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Guide to the Insects of Connecticut. Part VI. The Diptera or True Flies. Fifth Fascicle: Midges and Gnats, State of Connecticut, State Geological and Natural History Survey Bulletin No. 80, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Insect and Disease Control in the Flower Garden / E. K. Wade, J. M. Wright, L. M. Berninger, University of Wisconsin Extention Service, Circular 592, March 1961 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Naturalist's Lexicon / Compiled by Robert S. Woods, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Revision of the Scale-Insects of Florida / G. B. Merrill, State Plant Board of Florida, Bulletin 1, January 1953 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Soft Scales Injurious to Deciduous Ornamentals / E. I. McDaniel, Agricultural Experiment Station, Michigan State College of Agriculture and Applied Science, Circular Bulletin No. 133, April 1930 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Water and Water Solutions of Organizc Compounds as Dips for the Soil of Potted Plants Infested with the Japanese Beetle / Walter E. Fleming, Reprinted from Journal of Agricultural Research, Vol. 33, No. 9, November 1, 1926 (Box 17, Folder 21)